<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Application</string>
    <string name="ada_s">    Augusta Ada King-Noel, Countess of Lovelace (née Byron; 10 December 1815 – 27 November 1852) was an English mathematician and writer, chiefly known for her work on Charles Babbage\'s proposed mechanical general-purpose computer, the Analytical Engine. She was the first to recognise that the machine had applications beyond pure calculation, and published the first algorithm intended to be carried out by such a machine. As a result, she is sometimes regarded as the first to recognise the full potential of a "computing machine" and the first computer programmer.
    Ada Lovelace was the only legitimate child of the poet Lord Byron, and his wife Anne Isabella Milbanke ("Annabella"), Lady Wentworth. All of Byron\'s other children were born out of wedlock to other women. Byron separated from his wife a month after Ada was born and left England forever four months later. He commemorated the parting in a poem that begins, "Is thy face like thy mother\'s my fair child! ADA! sole daughter of my house and heart?". He died of disease in the Greek War of Independence when Ada was eight years old. Her mother remained bitter and promoted Ad\'s interest in mathematics and logic in an effort to prevent her from developing her father\'s perceived insanity. Despite this, Ada remained interested in Byron and was, upon her eventual death, buried next to him at her request. She was often ill in her childhood. Ada married William King in 1835. King was made Earl of Lovelace in 1838, and Ada in turn became Countess of Lovelace.
Her educational and social exploits brought her into contact with scientists such as Andrew Crosse, Sir David Brewster, Charles Wheatstone, Michael Faraday and the author Charles Dickens, which she used to further her education. Ada described her approach as "poetical science"and herself as an ”Analyst ( Metaphysician)".When she was a teenager, her mathematical talents led her to a long working relationship and friendship with fellow British mathematician Charles Babbage, also known as"the father of computers", and in particular, Babbage\'s work on the Analytical Engine. Lovelace first met him in June 1833, through their mutual friend, and her private tutor, Mary Somerville.Between 1842 and 1843, Ada translated an article by Italian military engineer Luigi Menabrea on the engine, which she supplemented with an elaborate set of notes, simply called Notes. These notes contain what many consider to be the first computer program—that is, an algorithm designed to be carried out by a machine. Lovelace\'s notes are important in the early history of computers. She also developed a vision of the capability of computers to go beyond mere calculating or number-crunching, while many others, including Babbage himself, focused only on those capabilities.Her mindset of "poetical science" led her to ask questions about the Analytical Engine (as shown in her notes) examining how individuals and society relate to technology as a collaborative tool.She died of uterine cancer in 1852 at the age of 36.
    </string>
<string name="james_s">James Gosling received a Bachelor of Science from the University of Calgary  and his M.A. and Ph.D. from Carnegie Mellon University. He wrote a version of Emacs called Gosling Emacs (Gosmacs) while working toward his doctorate. He built a multi-processor version of Unix for a 16-way computer system[7] while at Carnegie Mellon University, before joining Sun Microsystems. He also developed several compilers and mail systems there.
Gosling was with Sun Microsystems between 1984 and 2010 (26 years). He got the idea for the Java VM while writing a program to port software from a PERQ by translating Perq Q-Code to VAX assembler and emulating the hardware. He left Sun Microsystems on April 2, 2010 after it was acquired by the Oracle Corporation,[8] citing reductions in pay, status, and decision-making ability, along with change of role and ethical challenges.[9] He has since taken a very critical stance towards Oracle in interviews, noting that "during the integration meetings between Sun and Oracle, where we were being grilled about the patent situation between Sun and Google, we could see the Oracle lawyer's eyes sparkle."[10] He clarified his position during the Oracle v Google trial over Android: "While I have differences with Oracle, in this case, they are on the right. Google totally slimed Sun. We were all really disturbed, even Jonathan Schwartz; he just decided to put on a happy face and tried to turn lemons into lemonade, which annoyed a lot of folks on Sun."[11] However, he approved of the court's ruling that APIs should not be copyrightable.[12]

In March 2011, Gosling left Oracle to work at Google. Six months later, he followed his colleague Bill Vass and joined a startup called Liquid Robotics. In late 2016, Liquid Robotics was aquired by Boeing.[14] Following the aquisition, Gosling left Liquid Robotics to work at Amazon Web Services as Distinguished Engineer in May 2017.[15]

He is an adviser at the Scala company Typesafe Inc., Independent Director at Jelastic,[17] and Strategic Advisor for Eucalyptus, and is a board member of DIRTT Environmental Solutions.[19]

He is known for his love of proving "the unknown" and has noted that his favorite irrational number is √2. He has a framed picture of the first 1,000 digits of √2 in his office.
</string>
    <string name="ada_c">
奥古斯塔国王艾达诺尔，洛夫莱斯伯爵夫人（NéE拜伦；1815年12月10日–1852年11月27日）是英国数学家、作家，主要以她对查尔斯先生提出了通用计算机的机械工作，分析机。她是第一个认识到这台机器的应用超出了纯粹计算的范围，并公布了第一个打算由这种机器执行的算法。因此，她有时被认为是第一个认识到“计算机”和第一个计算机程序员的全部潜力的人。
阿达·洛芙莱斯是诗人拜伦勋爵的唯一合法的孩子，和他的妻子Anne Isabella Milbanke（“安娜贝拉”），Lady Wentworth。拜伦所有的其他孩子都是非婚生的。艾达出生后一个月，拜伦与妻子分居，四个月后离开了英国。他怀念离别诗中开始，“你的脸像你的母亲是我的美丽的孩子！艾达！我的房子和心灵的唯一女儿？”在艾达八岁的时候，他死于希腊独立战争中的疾病。她的母亲仍然很痛苦，并提升了她对数学和逻辑的兴趣，努力阻止她发展她父亲的精神错乱。尽管如此，艾达仍然对拜伦感兴趣，并在她的死后，在她的要求下安葬在他旁边。她童年时经常生病。艾达于1835嫁给了William King。国王在1838 Earl洛夫莱斯，和艾达成为洛夫莱斯伯爵夫人。
她的教育和社会利用带她接触到的科学家如安德鲁·克罗塞、David Brewster爵士、Charles Wheatstone、迈克尔·法拉第和查尔斯·狄更斯，她用她进一步教育。艾达称她为“诗意的科学方法”，自己作为一个“分析师（形而上学）”。当她十几岁的时候，她的数学才能使她长期的工作关系，同英国数学家查尔斯·巴贝奇的友谊，也被称为“计算机之父”，和特别是，巴贝奇的研究分析引擎。色鬼第一次见到他是在1833年6月，通过他们共同的朋友，和她的私人家教，Mary Somerville。1842和1843之间，艾达翻译的意大利军事工程师Luigi Menabrea在发动机上的一篇文章，她补充了一个精心设置的笔记，简称笔记。这些注释包含了许多被认为是第一个计算机程序，也就是说，设计了由机器执行的算法。色鬼的笔记电脑的早期历史是很重要的。她还开发了一个视觉的计算机的能力，超越了单纯的计算或数字运算，而其他许多人，包括Babbage自己，只关注那些能力。她的心态“诗意科技”使她问问题的分析引擎（如笔记所示）对个人和社会的关系技术作为一个协作工具。她死于子宫癌，1852在36岁。  </string>
    <string name="james_c">
杰姆斯Gosling从卡尔加里大学获得了他的硕士和博士学位从卡内基梅隆大学理学士。He wrote a version of Emacs called Gosling Emacs (Gosmacs) while working toward his doctorate. 在卡内基梅隆大学加入Sun微系统之前，他为建立了一个16路计算机系统的UNIX多处理器版本。他还在那里开发了一些编译器和邮件系统。
小鹅是Sun微系统公司的1984和2010之间（26年）。他想到了java VM在写程序端口软件从PERQ翻译PERQ Q VAX汇编和仿真硬件。他离开Sun微系统公司在2010年4月2日被甲骨文公司收购，[ 8 ]以减薪，地位和决策能力，随着角色和伦理挑战变化。[ 9 ]他已经对Oracle在采访中一个非常关键的立场，指出“在阳光和甲骨文之间的整合会议，我们被烤的关于Sun和谷歌之间的专利情况，我们可以看到Oracle的律师的眼睛闪闪发光。”[ 10 ]，他阐明了自己的立场的Oracle和谷歌在Android中的审判：“我虽然差异与甲骨文，在这种情况下，他们是对的。谷歌完全使太阳。我们都很不安，甚至Jonathan Schwartz；他只是决定放上一张快乐的脸，试图把柠檬变成柠檬水，使很多人对太阳。”[ 11 ]然而，他同意法院的裁决，API不应该受版权保护的。[ 12 ]

2011年3月，小鹅离开甲骨文在谷歌工作。六个月后，他跟他的同事Bill Vass加入了一家名为液态机器人。在2016年底，液态机器人获得由波音。[ 14 ]继兼并、小鹅离开液体机器人在亚马逊网络服务在2017年5月成为杰出的工程师的工作。[ 15 ]

他是一个顾问在Scala公司类型安全的公司，独立董事在jelastic，[ 17 ]和战略顾问为桉树，是DIRTT环境解决方案的董事会成员。[ 19 ]

他知道他的爱证明“未知”，指出他最喜欢的无理数√2。他有一个图片的√2前1000位在他的办公室。
    </string>
</resources>
